Faculty-Student Association; Records ua310
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Faculty-Student Association Records
1952-1976
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Faculty-Student Association (University at Albany)
ua310
4.0 cubic ft.
The Faculty-Student Association Records document the day-to-day operations of this non-profit organization which provided ancillary services to the university community.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted with the exception of one folder lsited below.
Acquisition Information
University Auxiliary Services transferred the records of the Faculty-Student Association to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Biographical Sketch
The Faculty-Student Association (FSA) developed in 1950 at the New York State College for Teachers. This non-profit corporation operated and financed ancillary enterprises associated with higher education, such as the bookstore and dining services. The college’s co-op bookstore began in the 1920s, but effective September 1, 1950 the FSA assumed its assets, liabilities and ownership. Similarly the College cafeteria opened in the early 1940s and in 1951, the FSA assumed the assets, liabilities and ownership of the cafeteria.
FSA diversified into new areas beyond the book store and dining services during the next two decades. This included check cashing, operation of a barber shop and beauty parlor, real estate investment, management of the College bowling alley, provision of linen and dry cleaning services, loans, film service and supervision of scholarship endowments. With a high demand for housing, the FSA in the early 1950s began to acquire area single-family homes and apartments by lease or purchase to provide homes for faculty and students. The FSA sold these homes during the 1970s. In 1965 the FSA purchased the Mohawk Campus, several parcels of land along the Mohawk River near the Northway, and Goodman Place, adjacent to the University's recreational facility Camp Dippikill, in 1966. Both were later sold as well.
The organization employed nearly 200 full-time staff members as of 1967 and 275 by 1972. Hundreds of students also filled temporary positions with the organization. An executive director (later a general manager) oversaw the day-to-day operations of the FSA. A Board of Directors provided policy direction for the FSA and had representatives from administration, faculty and students.
In 1966, New York State required FSA to begin to enter into formal, yearly contracts for services with the State University of New York Central Office. Two of these contracts are included in the records.
During the late 1960s and early 1970s, the FSA experienced a cash shortage and students began to demand control over the FSA budget, specifically its allocation of funds. The Albany Student Press published a series of investigative reports on the FSA during the fall of 1971 seeking to provide students with a better understanding of the association and its holdings. This demand for reform resulted in greater student representation on the Board of Directors, elimination of free meals for dorm directors, resident assistants and international students and allowing student input on the hiring of key FSA personnel. In 1975 students took even greater control of the Board and its leadership. In addition to the divesting of real estate, there were other financial restructuring changes, especially the contracting of bookstore operations in 1972 to a private vendor who paid the FSA a percentage of gross sales.
In 1976, prompted by its student members, the FSA changed its name to University Auxiliary Services (UAS) to avoid confusion with other groups with the words student association in their names. The UAS continued to invest in and provide campus services (often through corporate partners) such as dining, vending, banking and the bookstore. This non-profit corporation remains part of the University community today.
Scope and Contents
The Faculty-Student Association (FSA) Records document the administrative and financial operations of this non-profit organization which provided ancillary services to the campus community. The majority of records are from the 1960s and 1970s. There is a smaller percentage of files from the 1950s, but none from the organization's founding in 1950. In 1976 the organization changed its name to University Auxiliary Services and there is a small number of materials from 1976 reflecting this transition.
The records consist of financial reports, audits, by-laws, correspondence, studies and meeting minutes. There also are some brochures and background materials on the FSA.
The archivist retained the original order and folder titles.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized alphabetically. There are no series.
College stores; Student movements; Universities and colleges--Costs; Universities and colleges--Food service; Albany (N.Y.); Minutes; Bylaws (administrative records); Correspondence; Financial Records; Audits; UAlbany Finance & Business; State University of New York at Albany, Faculty-Student Association; State University of New York at Albany
- 727 Madison Avenue Yearly Accounting Budget, 1955 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 1)
- Ad Hoc Committee on Finance, 1971 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 2)
- Administration and Staff list, 1965 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 3)
- Agreements, 1966; 1971 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 4)
- Annual Report, 1965; ca. 1971; 1973 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 5)
- Annual Report and Accounting Committee, 1970-1971 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 6)
- Application for Employment, Undated (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 7)
- Article V, 1965-1966; 1968-1969; Undated (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 8)
- Audit Report of Financial Operating Practices, 1974 April 30 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 9)
- Audited Financial Statements, 1967-1970 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 10)
- Auditors, 1963-1966 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 11)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1970 February 28 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 12)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1970 March 31 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 13)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1970 April 30 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 14)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1970 May 31 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 15)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1970 June 30 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 16)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1970 August 31 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 17)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1970 September 30 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 18)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1970 October 31 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 19)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1970 November 30 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 20)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1970 December 30 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 21)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1971 January 31 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 22)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1971 February 28 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 23)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1971 March 31 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 24)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1971 April 30 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 25)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1971 August 31 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 26)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1971 September 30 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 27)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1971 October 31 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 28)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1971 November 30 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 29)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1971 December 31 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 30)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1972 January 31 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 31)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1972 February 29 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 32)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1972 March 31 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 33)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1972 April 30 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 34)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1972 May 31 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 35)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1972 July 31 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 36)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1972 August 31 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 37)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1972 September 30 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 38)
- Auxiliary Services, Bookstore, Vending, 1973 February 28 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 39)
- Board Minutes, 1972-1974 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 40-41)
- Board of Directors, 1952; 1955-1957; 1960; 1962-1966 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 42)
- Board of Directors, 1970 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 43)
- Board of Directors, 1971 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 44-48)
- Board of Directors, 1972 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 49-52)
- Board of Directors, 1973-1974 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 53)
- Board of Directors, 1974-1975 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 54-55)
- Board of Directors, 1975-1976 (Box 1 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 56-57)
- Board of Directors, Minutes of Meetings, 1965-1969 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 1)
- Board of Directors, Unbound Binder, 1971-1972 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 2-3)
- Board of Directors, Personnel and Salary Committee, 1971-1972; Undated (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 4)
- Bookstore, 1971 July 02 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 5)
- Bookstore and Auxiliary Services, 1968 December 31 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 6)
- Bookstore and Auxiliary Services, 1969 January 31 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 7)
- Bookstore and Auxiliary Services, 1969 February 28 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 8)
- Bookstore and Auxiliary Services, 1969 March 31 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 9)
- Bookstore and Auxiliary Services, 1969 April 30 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 15)
- Bookstore and Auxiliary Services, 1969 April (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 11)
- Bookstore and Auxiliary Services, 1969 May 31 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 12)
- Bookstore and Auxiliary Services, 1969 June 30 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 13)
- Bookstore and Auxiliary Services, 1969 October 31 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 14)
- Bookstore and Barbershop - [RESTRICTED], 1965-1967; Undated (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 15)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Must consult archivist before viewing this material.
- Bookstore Chargers and Faculty Desk Copies, 1972 January 11 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 16)
- Bookstore- Financial Statements, 1971 August 31 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 17)
- Bookstore- Financial Statements, 1971 September 30 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 18)
- Bookstore- Financial Statements, 1971 October 31 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 19)
- Bookstore- Financial Statements, 1971 November 30 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 20)
- Bookstore- Financial Statements, 1971 December 31 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 21)
- Bookstore- Financial Statements, 1972 January 31 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 22)
- Bookstore- Financial Statements, 1972 February 29 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 23)
- Bookstore- Financial Statements, 1972 March 31 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 24)
- Bookstore- Financial Statements, 1972 April 30 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 25)
- Bookstore- Financial Statements, 1972 May 31 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 26)
- Bookstore- Financial Statements, 1972 July 31 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 27)
- Bookstore- Financial Statements, 1972 September 30 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 28)
- Bookstore- Financial Statements, 1972 October 31 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 29)
- Bookstore- Financial Statements, 1972 November 30 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 30)
- Bookstore- Financial Statements, 1972 December 31 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 31)
- Bookstore- Financial Statements, 1973 January 31 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 32)
- Brochures and Backgrounds, Undated (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 33)
- Budget, 1968-1969 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 34)
- Budget, 1969 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 35)
- Budget, 1969-1970 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 36)
- Budget, 1970-1971 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 37)
- Budget, 1971-1972 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 38)
- Budget, 1972-1973 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 39)
- By-Laws, 1965-1969 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 40)
- By-Laws, 1970-1974; Undated (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 41)
- Campus Center Financial Statements, 1972 June 30 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 42)
- Certification of Dissolution, 1967 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 43)
- Chancellor's Task Force on Faculty-Student Association, 1975 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 44)
- Chart of Accounts, 1966 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 45)
- Contracts between SUNY and FSA SUNYA, Inc., 1966; 1968 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 46)
- Copyrights and Patents, Royalty Payments, 1970; 1972-1973 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 47)
- Correspondence, 1959-1962; 1964-1968 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 48)
- Correspondence, 1970-1976; Undated (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 49)
- Directors Reports, ca. 1968; 1970 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 50)
- Estimated and Preliminary Budgets, 1964-1965; Undated (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 51)
- Extension Teaching Schedule, 1963 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 52)
- Faculty Collections Memo, Undated (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 53)
- Faculty Council Albany, 1965; Undated (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 54)
- Faculty-Student Association Chronological File, 1966-1967 (Box 2 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 55)
- Faculty-Student Association Chronological File, 1967-1968 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 1-2)
- Faculty-Student Association Chronological File, 1968-1969 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 3)
- Faculty-Student Association Chronological File, 1970-1971 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 4)
- Faculty-Student Association Chronological File, 1971-1972 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 5-6)
- Financial Reports, 1969-1970 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 7)
- Financial Statements, 1954 June 30 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 8)
- Financial Statements, 1956 June 30 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 9)
- Financial Statements, 1958 June (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 10)
- Financial Statements, 1959 June; 1959 November (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 11)
- Financial Statements, 1960 June (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 12)
- Financial Statements, 1961 June (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 13)
- Financial Statements, 1963 June (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 14)
- Financial Statements, 1964 June (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 15)
- Financial Statements, 1965 June (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 16)
- Financial Statements, 1966 March; 1966 June (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 17)
- Financial Statements, 1967 June (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 18)
- Financial Statements, 1968 February (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 19)
- Financial Statements, 1968 June (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 20)
- Financial Statements, 1969 June 30 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 21)
- Financial Statements, 1970 June 30 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 22)
- Financial Statements, 1971 June 30 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 23)
- Financial Statements, 1972 June 30 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 24)
- Financial Statements, 1973 February 28 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 25)
- Financial Statements, 1973 June 30 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 26)
- Financial Statements (without audit), 1975 June 30; 1976 June 30 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 27)
- Food Service Catering Menu, 1974; Undated (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 28)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1968 September 30 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 29)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1968 October 30 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 30)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1968 November 30 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 31)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1968 December 31 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 32)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1969 January 31 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 33)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1969 February 28 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 34)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1969 March 31 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 35)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1969 March (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 36)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1969 April 30 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 37)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1969 April (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 38)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1969 May 31 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 39)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1969 May (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 40)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1969 June 30 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 41)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1969 October 31 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 42)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1969 October (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 43)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1969 November 30 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 44)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1969 December 31 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 45)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1970 January 31 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 46)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1970 February 28 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 47)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1970 March 31 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 48)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1970 April 30 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 49)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1970 May 31 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 50)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1970 July 31 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 51)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1970 September 30 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 52)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1970 October 31 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 53)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1970 November 30 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 54)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1970 December 31 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 55)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1971 February 28 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 56)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1971 March 31 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 57)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1971 April 30 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 58)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1971 May 31 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 59)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1971 July 31 (Box 3 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 60)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1971 August 31 (Box 4 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 1)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1971 September 30 (Box 4 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 2)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1971 October 31 (Box 4 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 3)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1971 November 30 (Box 4 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 4)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1971 December 31 (Box 4 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 5)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1972 January 31 (Box 4 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 6)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1972 February 29 (Box 4 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 7)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1972 March 31 (Box 4 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 8)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1972 April 30 (Box 4 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 9)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1972 May 31 (Box 4 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 10)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1972 July 31 (Box 4 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 11)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1972 August 31 (Box 4 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 12)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1972 September 30 (Box 4 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 13)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1972 October 31 (Box 4 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 14)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1972 November 30 (Box 4 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 15)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1972 December 31 (Box 4 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 16)
- Food Service- Financial Statements, 1973 January 31 (Box 4 (Faculty-Student Association Records ), Folder 17)